<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on A Simple Blog</title>
    <link>https://mrjoh3.github.io/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on A Simple Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mrjoh3.github.io/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shiny and Rmarkdown Image Galleries</title>
      <link>https://mrjoh3.github.io/p/shiny-image-gallery-examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrjoh3.github.io/p/shiny-image-gallery-examples/</guid>
      <description>Some time ago I had to implement an image gallery within a shiny application. A simple grid of small thumbnail images where clicking opens the full image. Nothing complicated, but I did have several requirements:
The gallery needed to render from a folder of images The gallery interface and thumbnails needed to be responsive The gallery needed to link to other shiny UI Images come from one location, no need for generating thumbnails  There is a wide variety of javascript image gallery implementations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggtrack</title>
      <link>https://mrjoh3.github.io/packages/ggtrack-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrjoh3.github.io/packages/ggtrack-package/</guid>
      <description>ggtrack   Sometimes in a workplace it is hard to know exactly where or when a specific chart has been produced. This is especially true when someone has copied a chart out of a report to use somewhere else. The ggtrack package aims to solve this problem by embedding enough metadata in the charts image to identify the source and the exact time it was produced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cytoscape</title>
      <link>https://mrjoh3.github.io/packages/cytoscape-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrjoh3.github.io/packages/cytoscape-package/</guid>
      <description>A HTMLWidget wrapper for the Cytoscape.js graph / network visualisation and analysis library. There are already a number of existing R packages for Cytoscape such as the Bioconductor package and the official Cytoscape Widget. The purpose of this package is to make the process of producing a basic chart as simple as possible.
Installation devtools::install_github(&amp;#39;mrjoh3/cytoscape&amp;#39;)  A Minimal Example library(cytoscape) nodes &amp;lt;- data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mapedit.addin</title>
      <link>https://mrjoh3.github.io/packages/mapedit-addin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrjoh3.github.io/packages/mapedit-addin/</guid>
      <description>mapedit.addin  
The goal of mapedit.addin is to simplify the creation of spatial data by wrapping the mapedit package. As you can see in the code below the mapedit package already makes the process very simple.
library(mapview) library(mapedit) new_spatial_data &amp;lt;- mapview() %&amp;gt;% editMap() All mappedit.addin does is wrap this piece of code in an RStudio addin. This means that the process of creating spatial data and saving it to file is completed using only GUI tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>c3</title>
      <link>https://mrjoh3.github.io/packages/2018-08-19-c3-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrjoh3.github.io/packages/2018-08-19-c3-package/</guid>
      <description>The c3 package is a wrapper, or htmlwidget, for the C3 javascript charting library by Masayuki Tanaka. You will find this package useful if you are wanting to create a chart using R and embedding it in a Rmarkdown document or Shiny App.
The C3 library is very versatile and includes a lot of options. Currently this package wraps most of the C3 options object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>pier</title>
      <link>https://mrjoh3.github.io/packages/pier-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrjoh3.github.io/packages/pier-package/</guid>
      <description>The pier package (pronounced pie-r) is a wrapper, or htmlwidget, for the d3pie javascript library by Benjamin Keen. If you are just wanting to generate a pie chart the d3pie website has a fantastic generator that will create the code that you need. If you are wanting create a chart using R for embedding in a Rmarkdown document or Shiny App, then you are in the right place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtering Spatial Data with Crosstalk</title>
      <link>https://mrjoh3.github.io/p/filtering-spatial-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrjoh3.github.io/p/filtering-spatial-data/</guid>
      <description>hljs.highlightAll(); In a previous post I wanted to look at the daily pattern of motor vehicle accidents across the state of Victoria. What I am really interested in though is the accidents in my local area.
To do this I am going to use leaflet, sf to handle all the spatial data and crosstalk to filter the data visible in the map. The crosstalk package enables a level of interactivity that is usually reserved for more complex server (shiny) based applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another blog about a blog</title>
      <link>https://mrjoh3.github.io/p/another-blog-about-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrjoh3.github.io/p/another-blog-about-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>Currently I mostly work with R and use it for statistics, modelling, GIS and web / pdf based reporting. Therefore the choice of Blogdown seemed simple enough. You will find many existing posts about others setting up their blogs in a similar way. Further, the book blogdown: Creating Websites with R Markdown by Yihui Xie et al. covers everything you need to know about the process. Here, I am only going to discuss the few specific issues I had to deal with to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating Spatial Data</title>
      <link>https://mrjoh3.github.io/p/animating-spatial-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrjoh3.github.io/p/animating-spatial-data/</guid>
      <description>#rstats + #sf + #ggplot2 + #gganimate = a great way to visualise some sobering data. Only accidents where alcohol was involved. Remember each frame only accidents from a single day. See code gist https://t.co/wqEcYku2us and get data from #vicroads api https://t.co/cBX1kBz9iw pic.twitter.com/tNobkLQQQH — Matt Johnson (@mrjoh3) July 18, 2018    library(dplyr) library(sf) library(ggplot2) library(gganimate) shp &amp;lt;- st_read(&amp;#39;~/Documents/Matt/GIS/shp&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;Crashes_Last_Five_Years&amp;#39;, quiet = TRUE) %&amp;gt;% filter(ALCOHOL_RE == &amp;#39;Yes&amp;#39;) %&amp;gt;% mutate(date = as.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
